Zachary Hewlett

Developer with 4+ years of experience in building web applications and static sites, and in writing technical documentation for applications, processes, and testing.

Life-long learner and effective communicator with an eye for detail and a passion for accessible visual design.

EXPERIENCE

Mphasis - Associate Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

Maintained robotic testing software to add new features and resolve issues, including support for a cloud-based testing platform.

Wrote and conducted integration test plans for new robotic software releases.

Wrote automated test scripts using Robot Framework to reproduce scenarios for support team. Led Robot Framework training classes.

Created Power Automate flows to improve visibility into support team inquiries and reduce customer ticket close time.

LGI Homes - IT DevOps Analyst

JANUARY 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Built business-critical mortgage pipeline web app using Django to support company's joint venture.

Performed training demonstrations for nationwide web application deployment.

Developed asset management web app to replace spreadsheet workflow, improving asset management efficiency across over 100 locations.

Managed domains and SSL certificates to keep external websites and internal web apps secure.

Worked with Internal Controls team to update IT policy documentation.

Wrote, edited, and consolidated documentation for IT architecture and processes into team handbook.

LGI Homes – IT Intern

JUN 2018 - JAN 2019, DEC 2017 - JAN 2018, JUL 2017 - SEP 2017

Designed and developed sales center management web app to improve efficiency in performing IT installs nationwide.

Refreshed legacy ColdFusion web apps to provide responsive layouts and to better reflect updated branding.

NOV – Software Design Intern

DEC 2014 - JAN 2015, JUN 2014 - AUG 2014

Designed and developed iOS and Android mobile app for offshore employees.

CONTACT

Pearland, TX
zachhewlett@outlook.com
https://portfolio.huedev.me

SKILLS

HTML • CSS • JavaScript

TypeScript • React • Next.js

Tailwind CSS • Bootstrap

Python • Django

ColdFusion

MySQL • SQL Server
GitHub • Azure DevOps

EDUCATION

University of HoustonBS in Computer Science
2014-2018

CERTIFICATIONS

ITIL 4 Foundation 2020

CompTIA IT Fundamentals+ 2019